<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux How To on solc0nf</title>
    <link>https://solc0nf.github.io/linux-howto/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux How To on solc0nf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 19:54:13 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://solc0nf.github.io/linux-howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apache2 Custom Site With Self Signed Certificate</title>
      <link>https://solc0nf.github.io/linux-howto/apache2-custom-site-with-self-signed-certificate/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 20:20:28 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://solc0nf.github.io/linux-howto/apache2-custom-site-with-self-signed-certificate/index.html</guid>
      <description>For this activity, we will use a Debian 12 VM with apache installed. The debian installer gives us an option to install a web server (among other things) during the installation process. In case we need to install apache2 after the machine has booted up, it can be done with apt install apache2.
Either way, once you have apache installed, we can go to http://your_server_ip and we&amp;rsquo;ll get the default apache landing page as show inthe screen grab below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encrypt and Share Files With Gpg</title>
      <link>https://solc0nf.github.io/linux-howto/encrypt-and-share-files-with-gpg/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 20:17:39 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://solc0nf.github.io/linux-howto/encrypt-and-share-files-with-gpg/index.html</guid>
      <description>Today, we will look at encrypting and sharing files securely using gpg. GnuPG (GPG) is a tool used to encrypt data and create digital signatures.
For our exercise, we will consider two users on two different linux systems. They are running a mustard smuggling operations out of an undisclosed location and need to share information securely, to avoid any interception by Mustardpol. 😉
User1 : sierra1 with email sierra1@mustardops.org User2 : november2 with email november2@mustardops.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Passwords in Linux</title>
      <link>https://solc0nf.github.io/linux-howto/secure-passwords-in-linux/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 20:15:17 +0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://solc0nf.github.io/linux-howto/secure-passwords-in-linux/index.html</guid>
      <description>There are many utilities in Linux that help us in generating random passwords. The neccessity of having a strong password is well known. The problem with random passwords is that it is nearly impossible for us remember them. Using a password manager like KeePassX or KeePass2. That way, you only have to remember one password, the master pasword to unlock your password vault. This leads to another monkey&amp;rsquo;s tail scenario. If we loose/forget the master password, we you&amp;rsquo;re doomed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>